<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Org | Dev and Such]]></title>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/categories/org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-10T08:28:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://echosa.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Zwahr]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm Slowly Getting ORGanized]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2010/05/11/im-slowly-getting-organized/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-11T17:04:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2010/05/11/im-slowly-getting-organized</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve found myself using ORG mode a LOT lately, mostly at work. I&rsquo;m really come to like it, and it has basically because my todo list for work. Of all the useful features ORG has, there is one that I never learned about until recently: links. I&rsquo;m sure I should have known about these long ago, but for some reason I didn&rsquo;t.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Anyway, links are just what the name implies: clickable links to other places (though, the mouse is not necessary). This can be to a url, a file, or even a specific place in a file (i.e. line number, certain word, etc). I find this extremely useful as a programmer.</p>

<p>For example, I find a bug in a program. I place a TODO item in my org document to fix the bug. Inside the description, I can then place a link to the file where the code to be fixed is, or more specifically, I can link it to an exact function/method or even line number! Then, when I get around to that TODO item, I simply activate the link, and the file loads up, ready to fix!</p>

<p>There is one small caveat though. By default, org will open the file in a different window. Some might like this, but I have one main window in my emacs frame that is for working in (org files, source code, etc). So, when I&rsquo;ve viewing my org document and activate a link, I want the file to load in that same window. A quick Google search revealed a simple fix for this: customize the variable <code>org-link-frame-setup</code> and change <code>file</code> to use the function <code>find-file</code> instead of <code>find-file-other-window</code>. Easy enough!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
