<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Xdebug | Dev and Such]]></title>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/categories/xdebug/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-17T23:51:10-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://echosa.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Zwahr]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[XDebug and Truncated Output]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2012/08/22/xdebug-and-truncated-output/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T08:42:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2012/08/22/xdebug-and-truncated-output</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having used Zend_Debug::dump() with XDebug for quite some time, I&rsquo;ve finally gotten tired of seeing truncated output. What I mean is, when I have Zend_Debug::dump() display a stack trace (for instance), it will show the first few lines then truncate with and ellipsis. This is fairly useless. Sure, I <em>could</em> go to the error log, but there&rsquo;s a reason I&rsquo;m dumping this to the screen (when I&rsquo;m in developer mode and have the show debug info flag for my application turned on&hellip; don&rsquo;t worry, this doesn&rsquo;t happen in production). For a while now I&rsquo;ve just put up with it, thinking it an issue with Zend_Debug.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I was wrong.</p>

<p>Its actually an issue with XDebug and the amount of information it will show. Even just using var_dump by itself (Zend_Debug uses it internally) will result in truncation. However, this is a one line fix. In your php.ini, put this:
    xdebug.var_display_max_data = -1
or in your application config, you can set this at run time like this:
    phpSettings.xdebug.var_display_max_data = -1
The -1 tells XDebug to display an infinite amount of data. No more truncation!</p>

<p>You might ask why I&rsquo;m Zend_Debug::dump()-ing my stack traces anyway, instead of just printing or echoing them. Well, because SHUT UP THAT&rsquo;S WHY. Seriously, though, its just something I&rsquo;ve done since I started using Zend Framework that has stuck around with me. I&rsquo;m only human, which is slightly better than <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zQTimBTkYzw">almost human</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
