<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Macosx | Dev and Such]]></title>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/categories/macosx/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-08-18T09:53:54-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://echosa.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Zwahr]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac OS X Screen Locking Made Easy]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2012/07/17/mac-os-x-screen-locking/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-17T11:49:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2012/07/17/mac-os-x-screen-locking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In &ldquo;why the hell isn&rsquo;t the more known or documented better&rdquo; news, a coworker of mine discovered and shared with me a neat little trick for locking Mac OS X: Control-Shift-Eject.</p>

<p>Mind you, this will only work if you are using an actual Apple keyboard with an eject key. However, prior to this, the screen locking solutions I found were as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>have the screen saver turn on, possibly via a hot corner or hot key that I&rsquo;d have to manual set</li>
<li>choose &lsquo;Lock Screen&rsquo; from the menulet that you can enable via Keychain Access -> Preferences -> General -> Show keychain status in menu bar</li>
<li>write a custom applescript or Automator app/service to lock the screen, then set that to a key binding (per bullet point 1, above)</li>
<li>Do a fast logout by clicking on the user switching menulet (if it is turned on in System Preferences) and selecting &ldquo;Login Window&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<p>Each of these either is a hassle or has unwanted side-effects that I didn&rsquo;t like. For instance, the fast logout option wasn&rsquo;t so bad, except instead of being left at a lock screen, it leaves you at a login screen, which means two things:</p>

<ol>
<li>you have to select your account before entering your password (two step process, explained below), and</li>
<li>other people have the option to login (not a <em>huge</em> deal, but not really desired by me at this point, and yes there are other accounts on my system).</li>
</ol>


<p>The biggest of these two, for me, was number 1. When the screen is <em>locked</em>, all I have to do is press any key to &ldquo;wake up&rdquo;, then type my password. That&rsquo;s not the case when you&rsquo;re at a login screen, of course. Having to use the mouse or keyboard to first select my user, <em>then</em> be prompted for my password became a hassle.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not sure if this was added in Lion or previous versions of OS X, but I&rsquo;m certainly glad to know it exists. So much so, in fact, I decided I should share this knowledge with the world. I know it doesn&rsquo;t particularly pertain to development, but I wanted to record it somewhere, if for no other reason than to have a resource where I can go back and remember &ldquo;what was the locking key command?&rdquo; in case I forget in the future.</p>

<p>So, yeah. There you go. Enjoy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
