<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Osx | Dev and Such]]></title>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/categories/osx/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-13T08:50:56-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://echosa.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Zwahr]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emacs With TRAMP Causing OS X Kernel Panic]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2013/02/01/emacs-with-tramp-causing-os-x-kernel-panic/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-01T09:25:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2013/02/01/emacs-with-tramp-causing-os-x-kernel-panic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve had a couple of kernel panics while using my MacBook lately, and I have figured out the culprit. It&rsquo;s Emacs, specifically when using TRAMP (in my case, to open a file via sudo).</p>

<!--more-->


<p>So, here&rsquo;s the deal. I&rsquo;m running OS X version 10.8.2 on a 15&#8221; MacBook Pro with Retina Display and have Emacs version 24.2.1 installed with <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/">Homebrew</a> without GUI support since I run Emacs via terminal. On this setup, I can reproduce my issue without fail. Here&rsquo;s how to do so (careful if you try this as it could cause a kernel panic):</p>

<ol>
<li>Open Emacs (might have to be in a terminal, which can be forced with <code>emacs -nw</code>)</li>
<li>Open a file with TRAMP, in my case for sudo access. To do this, if you are using ido-mode, then type <code>C-x C-f</code> and type <code>//sudo:root@localhost:/</code> (note the double forward slash at the beginning) and you should be asked for your password. After you give you password, finish typing the file name (in my case, <code>etc/php.ini</code>). If you aren&rsquo;t using ido-mode, you only need to type <code>C-x C-f</code> followed by <code>/sudo:root@localhost:/etc/php.ini</code>).</li>
<li>Now that you have a TRAMP process running, exit Emacs.</li>
</ol>


<p>If you have the same issue as me, exiting Emacs will cause a kernel panic. Killing the buffer prior to exit doesn&rsquo;t help, and neither does killing the TRAMP buffer that opens. However, actually killing the TRAMP process allows Emacs to close properly. This can be done by finding the process in via <code>M-x list-processes</code> and using <code>(delete-process PROCESS-NAME)</code> to kill it.</p>

<p>Of course, when OS X kernel panics, you get the option to send an error report to Apple. I saved the panic report to a text file and examined it. The error given by the kernel is as follows:</p>

<pre><code>panic(cpu 2 caller 0xffffff802491ec9a): "negative open count (c, 16, 1)"@/SourceCache/xnu/xnu-2050.20.9/bsd/miscfs/specfs/spec_vnops.c:1813
</code></pre>

<p>Later is the very long panic report, I see</p>

<pre><code>BSD process name corresponding to current thread: sudo
</code></pre>

<p>which is what caused me to investigate TRAMP as the issue.</p>

<p>Honestly, I don&rsquo;t know what&rsquo;s happening, and intend to do some Google searching to find out. If anyone has any information, please share. Otherwise, I advise everyone to be careful using TRAMP in the near future.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OS X Text Substitution]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2012/12/04/os-x-text-substitution/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-04T09:50:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2012/12/04/os-x-text-substitution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The last couple of versions of OS X have had a cool feature: user-added text substitutions. Meaning, you can set some placeholder text (like &ldquo;lod&rdquo;) that will be auto-corrected to something else (in my case, the <a href="http://www.disapprovallook.com">Look of Disapproval</a>).</p>

<!--more-->


<p>You can add your own text substitutions by going to <code>System Preferences -&gt; Language &amp; Text</code> and clicking on the Text tab. Click the + at the bottom left to add a new one, then choose what you want to type and what you want it to be replaced with. Make sure that &ldquo;Use symbol and text substitution&rdquo; and &ldquo;Correct spelling automatically&rdquo; are checked. (The latter is only necessary if you want OS X to do so; if you&rsquo;d rather do it yourself, you can leave this off I guess.)</p>

<p>At this point, if you&rsquo;re like me, you&rsquo;ll think you&rsquo;re good to go. You&rsquo;ll go to Mail or Textedit and try it out, and it will work. You&rsquo;ll then go to, for instance, Messages and try to use your new substitution only to find out that it <em>doesn&rsquo;t</em> work! This frustrated me to no end, until a friend pointed out the missing piece of the puzzle.</p>

<p>Apparently, each application can determine its use of text substitutions. If your substitutions do not work in a particular application, simply go to <code>Edit -&gt; Substitutions</code> and make sure that &ldquo;Text Replacement&rdquo; is checked. Now your substitutions should work! (Go ahead, try it!)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mountain Lion, Safari, and Flash]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2012/09/04/mountain-lion-safari-flash/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-04T08:21:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2012/09/04/mountain-lion-safari-flash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, if you&rsquo;re like me and you upgraded to Mountain Lion (OSX 10.8) only to have Safari continuously tell you that Flash is a &ldquo;blocked plugin&rdquo; and is out-of-date (no matter how many times you update and install the latest), you&rsquo;re probably ready to rip your hair out (or use Chrome like a quitter). Well, here&rsquo;s how <em>I</em> fixed the issue. Hopefully this works for you, too.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Either in Finder or Terminal go to <code>/Library/Internet Plugins</code>. If you see <code>_Flash Player.plugin</code> (with the underscore in front), delete that and restart Safari. That fixed the issue for me. I&rsquo;m thinking that was some old version that, for some reason, was overriding the newer installed version (without the underscore). Strange, indeed.</p>

<p>Reference: <a href="https://discussions.apple.com/thread/4251341?start=0&amp;tstart=0">Relevant Apple Support Thread</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
