<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gopher | Dev and Such]]></title>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/categories/gopher/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-07-09T08:43:05-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://echosa.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Zwahr]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gopher-php and Phlog Update]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/gopher-php-update/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-12T14:37:53-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2015/01/12/gopher-php-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently updated my <a href="https://github.com/echosa/gopher-php">gopher-php</a> package on GitHub as well as the <a href="http://echosa.freeshell.org/">web interface to my phlog</a> that uses it.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Most of the updates came about due to a change in the Gopher server that is serving my gopherspace. We are now using <a href="http://gopherproxy.meulie.net/gophernicus.org/">Gophernicus</a> which supports some extra gophermap file types, most notably <code>h</code> for HTTP URLs.</p>

<p>Gophernicus brought with it some other changes as well, some of which required changes to not only the gopher-php library but my web frontend as well. While I was in there tinkering away anyway, I decided to finally get some items from my TODO list taken care of. Most notably, I added pagination as well as information about viewing the phlog via Gopher instead of HTTP.</p>

<p>Of course, the most interesting changes came in the form of updating the library and its unit tests. To my gleeful surprise, adding support for new gophermap item types (<code>h</code> and <code>i</code>, specifically) was as simple as updating a single switch statement; the rest of the library continued working and supported the new item types with no other changes. I should probably do something about that switch statement before it gets too unwieldy, though.</p>

<p>Anyway, it was nice to get some dev time in on this project. I do so much programming for other people and businesses and tend to spend my personal dev time on hobby projects. I&rsquo;m glad I was able to work on something that is personal but also practical and in production, instead of just a hobby project.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gopherpedia]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2014/03/17/gopherpedia/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-17T10:37:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2014/03/17/gopherpedia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, <a href="http://gopherpedia.com">this</a> exists.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>That&rsquo;s right. Someone wrote a Gopher wrapper/front end for Wikipedia! It&rsquo;s not quite perfect (links and stuff don&rsquo;t work) but it&rsquo;s Good Enough©.</p>

<p>The link above takes you to the web front end, but you can reach it the site through Gopher itself at gopher://gopherpedia.com.</p>

<p>Long live Gopher!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New GOPHER Library for PHP]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2014/02/25/new-gopher-library-for-php/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-25T11:45:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2014/02/25/new-gopher-library-for-php</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, I&rsquo;ve gone and done it. I&rsquo;ve created a library for reading and parsing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gopher_(protocol%29">GOPHER</a> files from PHP.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I&rsquo;ve recently been playing with GOPHER again, and it&rsquo;s been a great blast from the past. I even started a phlog (a GOPHER blog, basically). However, I realized that not everyone is awesome enough to use GOPHER, so I wanted to make my new phlog available via HTTP as well. Enter gopher-php.</p>

<p>You can find the library <a href="https://github.com/echosa/gopher-php">here on GitHub</a>. It is quite tailor-made for my own usage, so it is pretty incomplete in terms of GOPHER features and support.</p>

<p>To see it in action, you can check out <a href="http://echosa.freeshell.org">my phlog&rsquo;s http web frontend</a>. In comparision, you can see my phlog via the GOPHER protocol by either visiting <a href="gopher://sdf.org/1/users/echosa/phlog">this link</a> using a GOPHER client (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lynx_(web_browser%29">lynx</a> recommended) or by using a GOPHER web interface such as <a href="http://gopherproxy.meulie.net/sdf.org/1/users/echosa/phlog">this one</a> (link will take you to the phlog).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Going (Back to) Gopher]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2013/08/29/going-back-to-gopher/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-29T09:45:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2013/08/29/going-back-to-gopher</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Remember <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gopher_(protocol)">Gopher</a>? I do, barely. We learned/used it in grade school a couple of decades ago. Turns out it is still around.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>There are several resources for the existing gopher community. First and foremost, I&rsquo;d say check out <a href="http://gopher.floodgap.com">Floodgap</a>. They have a public gopher server, including a web interface that will let you read gopher pages in your browser. There&rsquo;s even several articles about <a href="http://gopher.floodgap.com/gopher/gw?gopher://gopher.floodgap.com:70/1/gopher">gopher&rsquo;s usage and relevance today</a>. Definitely worth at least a cursory glance.</p>

<p>Of course, having found this, I had to jump back in. You can find my own gopherspace hosted <a href="gopher://sdf.org/1/users/echosa">here</a> at <a href="http://sdf.org">SDF</a>. There you find, among other things, my phlog, which is gopher&rsquo;s version of a blog (blog = weB LOG, phlog = goPHer LOG).</p>

<p>Anyway, I figured I&rsquo;d just help spread the word. Long live gopher!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
