<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Php+ | Dev and Such]]></title>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/categories/php-plus/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-10T08:28:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://echosa.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Zwahr]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zf-mode Is No More... Viva Php+!]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2012/05/25/zf-mode-is-no-more-viva-php/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-25T15:22:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2012/05/25/zf-mode-is-no-more-viva-php</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My emacs package for working with php has just undergone a significant change. It is no longer called zf-mode.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Introducing: php+-mode!</p>

<p>PHP+-mode is just that. Its a mode for working with PHP files, <em>plus</em> other things (including some Zend Framework support [which is where it got its original name from]).</p>

<p>You can find it at <a href="https://github.com/echosa/phpplus-mode">https://github.com/echosa/phpplus-mode</a>. If you already use zf-mode, I suggest deleting it and getting php+. However, bear in mind that there have been changes to the names of customized variables. Please update (or reset) these accordingly.</p>

<p>If you use zf-mode and got it from MELPA, bear with me. I have submitted a pull request to the MELPA github with a new recipe for php+. Once that has been accepted, you&rsquo;ll be able to download php+ from MELPA once again.</p>

<p>In other news, I have just discovered the awesomeness of snippets via yasnippet.el. This has opened a <em>whole new world</em> to me, and means some big changes to php+. I&rsquo;ve already begun working on some major usage improvement using snippets that will make php+ a lot easier to use and, in my opinion, a lot more fun.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more details on php+!</p>

<p>Finally, I learned about yasnippet from <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/emacsrocks">@EmacsRocks</a> on Twitter. EmacsRocks puts out <a href="http://emacsrocks.com/">videos</a> show casing some of the cool things you can do with emacs. I highly recommend you check them out; they&rsquo;re typically only a couple minutes long.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
