<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Php+-mode | Dev and Such]]></title>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/categories/php-plus-mode/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-10T08:28:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://echosa.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Zwahr]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Php+-mode: An Apology, a Promise, and a Call for Help]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2013/01/13/php-plus-mode-an-apology/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-13T08:47:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2013/01/13/php-plus-mode-an-apology</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While browsing through some posts in the Google+ <a href="https://plus.google.com/communities/114815898697665598016">Emacs community</a>, I came across at least one post or comment where someone mentioned my <a href="https://github.com/echosa/phpplus-mode">php+-mode</a>. While it pleases me whenever I hear of someone using something I wrote, it reminded me of just how derelict and forgotten php+-mode has become. Thus, this post.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>First, the apology. I apologize to everyone, especially the Emacs and PHP communities, for lapsing on development and maintenance of php+-mode. To generate so much hype and interest, so much so that people actually use and recommend the package, then just stop development all together is pretty inexcusable. I do have an excuse - a couple, actually. Back at the end of October I began a new job and no longer write PHP code daily. In fact, I hardly write PHP code at all. Therefore, I do not use php+-mode and just haven&rsquo;t really thought about it. On top of that, between both my wife and I getting new jobs and some other life changes (on top of the past couple months of holidays), I haven&rsquo;t had as much spare time as I used to, so personal hobbies, interests, and projects have suffered (not just php+-mode).</p>

<p>Next, the promise. I promise that one of two things will happen. I will either continue development and maintenance of php+-mode (more on this in a bit) or I will officially call the project derelict. If the latter, which is the least desired option, I will try to find someone to take over. At bare minimum I will leave the project where it in on GitHub and in <a href="http://melpa.milkbox.net/">MELPA</a> so that people can still use it as is.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d much prefer the former option, however. I would like to see php+-mode grow, improve, and flourish, and I would very much enjoy being a part of that. Honestly, I miss working in elisp and would like to get back into it. That said, my time situation is still limited, at best, which brings me to my next point.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;d like to officially put out a call for help. Any elisp devs who would like to work on php+-mode, please feel free to fork the project and submit pull requests. There are currently two developers of php+-mode, and we just don&rsquo;t have the time to do it all.</p>

<p>So, there you have it, a state of php+-mode address. This project is important to me, and I think it is important for both the Emacs and PHP communities, especially the cross-section between. I&rsquo;d just forgotten how important it was until now, and I hope that I can manifest that personal importance into code.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
