<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Package-bundle | Dev and Such]]></title>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/categories/package-bundle/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://echosa.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-17T23:51:10-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://echosa.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Zwahr]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Package-bundle: Keep Track of Your Dependencies!]]></title>
    <link href="http://echosa.github.io/blog/2012/07/27/package-bundle-keep-track-of-your/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-27T16:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://echosa.github.io/blog/2012/07/27/package-bundle-keep-track-of-your</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have just pushed a new project to my github account: <a href="https://github.com/echosa/package-bundle">package-bundle</a>. It acts <em>sort of</em> like Vundle for vim, etc. It keeps track of your installed packages/dependencies (installed via package.el of course) and allows you to install them all with one command.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Why, you ask?</p>

<p>Well, I get tired of having to commit/push every time I install or delete a package via package.el. I already have my emacs config in github for version control and cloned into my Dropbox. This way, whenever I install or change something, it propagates to my other machines. However, if I have to install my config on a new machine, that doesn&rsquo;t have access to my Dropbox (for any reason), I can just clone it. However, in order for this to work, I had to keep all of my package.el packages stored in github as well, which caused a flurry of commits/pushes each time I installed or deleted a package.</p>

<p>package-bundle to the rescue! Instead of keeping all the installed packages themselves in github, I just keep package-bundle.el and my package-bundle file (which holds the references to the packages I need/want installed). I clone my config, load package-bundle, make sure that package-bundle-file points to the correct file (via customize), then run package-bundle-install. Assuming that package.el and the repositories (including the network connections between me and them) work just fine, all my wanted packages will be installed and ready to go (admittedly, after a bit, since package.el can be a bit, er, slow).</p>

<p>Bear in mind that this project is still <em>very</em> young. I encourage you to try it out and give me feed back (forking the project and submitting issues and/or pull requests on github would be <em>great</em>), but do make sure you back everything up first. Just sayin&#8217;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
